Hey. you.
Ooh.
It's okay.
I'm not going to hurt you.
Yeah.
Easy. boy.
That's it.
Hey. boy.
I'm not going to hurt you.
It's okay. Calm down.
Somebody!
Jesus Christ!
Somebody help!
Daddy. my horse!
Whoa! Whoa! Whoa!
He's going out!
Over here!
Whoa! Whoa! Easy!
Come on.
No. down! No!
I need to see the records
for a patient named Anna Morgan.
Are you a relative?
Well. no.
I'm sorry. sir.
We're a mental health facility.
Our records are private.
Well. she's been dead 24 years.
I don't think she'll mind.
I'm sorry.
It's impossible.
Look...
I've seen them before.
I've been up there.
Nice try.
The record rooms
are downstairs. guy.
You win.
Jerk off!
Are you in here. Anna?
Hello?
Excuse me. Mr. Morgan.
I was wondering if you'd have
a moment to speak with me.
My name's Rachel Keller.
I'm a writer with
the ''Seattle P.I.''
You want to know
about the horses.
I didn't mean to...
It's just I wasn't able to
find a number to reach you.
Every now and then.
a writer comes along...
heard about what happened.
What's left to write about.
though. I don't know.
I was hoping you had
just a few minutes.
Well. work never ends
around here. really...
but I guess I got a few.
So. what is it
you're writing. miss?
About horses in general
or just those that go strange?
I read you had
to put so many down.
Most put themselves down.
They drowned.
How'd they get out?
They just broke
through the fences
and ran to the shore.
So. they went crazy?
It would seem so. yes...
or maybe they just sense things
before we do.
So. where are your horses now?
I don't breed anymore.
I guess you wouldn't...
not after what happened.
That must've been hard...
on both of you...
you and your wife.
I'm sorry. miss.
what's your name again?
Rachel.
Well. Rachel...
you want to tell me what's
really on your mind?
Do you know what this is?
I think it's a message...
from your wife.
Anna's on this tape.
She's right there in that room.
You can see the lighthouse.
the horses...
Where'd you get that?
Shelter Mountain Inn.
Is that the only one?
I made a copy.
I've got a lot of work
to do today...
a lot of acres out there.
Minute I think I'm done
with one thing...
...another thing needs fixing.
You don't want to see this tape?
You're not even curious?
Curious?
No. I don't think so.
Mr. Morgan...
I can't help you.
Where's your daughter?
Maybe she couId help...
I don't have a daughter.
Excuse me?
What is it with reporters?
You take one person's tragedy
and force the world
to experience it...
spread it like sickness.
Mr. Morgan...
Tell me. miss...
what is it you think you know?
Then leave it alone.
Anna.
''Anna Morgan's...
...Hallucinations''?
What's wrong with you?
'''65. conceived.''
'''65. miscarriage.''
'''66. conceived.''
'''66. miscarriage.''
Christ. she wouldn't give up.
''Sessions terminated...
at father's request.
See Video Record S-M-0-1-5.''
Aidan?
Aidan. it's your mom.
Hi. Mom.
Honey. the house you drew
for me...
Uh-huh?
...where did you see it?
Did you see it in your head?
Is that why you drew it?
In my head?
Aidan... why did you draw
that house?
Because she told me to.
Who?
Who told you to?
The little girl.
She talks to you?
No.
She shows me things.
Did she show you the horses?
She doesn't like it in the barn.
The horses keep her up at night.
So. she still lives there?
No.
She lives in a dark place now.
You're getting a little old
to be crabbing out there. Cal.
Your body's about outlived
its warranty. you know.
You ain't exactly
the catch of the day.
Oh... let's see you
catch one better!
Yeah...
Good afternoon.
I'm Dr. Grasnik.
I think he was here before me.
Darby? Darby's always here.
Aren't you. Darby?
He's my son's boy.
Come over on the ferry. did you?
Yes.
Um... have you lived here long?
Born and raised.
Only doctor on the island.
Then you know the Morgans
and their daughter.
Do you know
their daughter?
Do you know their daughter?
What's this about?
Look. I'm sorry.
I-I don't know how to say this
but I'm seeing things
in my head-- images--
and so is my son.
My son. that...
that's why I'm here
and somehow.
I don't know how. but...
it's because of that girl.
Haven't heard anybody say that
in a long time.
She wanted a child
more than anything.
Poor Anna.
They tried hard for years
but sometimes
it's just not meant to be.
Then one winter. they went away.
When they came back
it was with Samara.
Adopted. they said.
Never did say from where.
Said the mother had died
of complications.
But they had their baby.
they had their horses--
everything was fine...
till Anna started coming
to see me.
Said she was
suffering visions...
seeing things...
horrible things...
like they'd been burned
inside her...
and it only happened
around Samara...
that the girl put them there.
Were you Samara's
doctor. too?
Was there anything wrong
with her?
You mean medically?
I mean whatever you mean.
When Darby. there. was born...
we knew something wasn't right
with him...
but we loved him anyway.
Takes work. you know.
Some people have limits.
So. what happened to her?
I referred them
to Eola Psychiatric
on the mainland.
I assume she's still there.
You don't know?
How can you not know?
We've been through...
a lot of hard years out here...
mean winters...
small hauls. no fish...
and that was long
before the horses.
See. when you live on an island
you catch a cold.
it's everybody's cold.
No offense. ma'am
but what the hell
does that mean?
It means ever since
that girl's been gone
things have been better.
1978.
Man. we're really going
back in time. here.
Yeah. the lady at reception said
it should still be here.
Should be. You say you're
the patient's father. right?
Yep. Richard Morgan. that's me.
What is your secret?
Diet and exercise. man.
No shit!
Yeah. that's all it takes.
You know. I'm
not an idiot.
You try and walk out
of here with my file
and I'll be on you
like white on rice.
You understand?
No. man.
I just want to watch it.
I'm responsible
for every file tape in here.
I have a system...
and I don't want anyone
disarranging it.
I'd never... disarrange...
Long as we understand
each other.
Okay. now I'm mad.
Does it say who was
the last person to watch it?
Yeah.
It was you.
Come on. come on!
The mobile unit you've called
is not responding
or is outside the coverage area.
You piece of shit!
Come on. Rachel.
Hello?
Mr. Morgan?
This is SM0015
Samara Morgan. hour 14.
Good. Very good.
So. what is it
that's keeping you awake?
You must sleep sometime.
Do you dream about something?
Samara?
Let's talk about the pictures.
How did you make them?
Samara?
How did you make these pictures?
I don't...
make them.
I see them...
and then...
they just... are.
Samara...
I need you to start
telling me the truth. okay?
Can I see my mommy?
No. Samara.
Not until we understand
what's wrong with you.
I love my mommy.
Yes. you do.
But you don't want to hurt her
anymore. now. do you?
You don't want to hurt anyone.
But I do. and I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
Well. that's why you're here.
So that I can help you
to make it stop.
He's going to leave me here.
Who?
Daddy.
They just want to help you.
Not Daddy.
Your daddy loves you.
Daddy loves the horses.
He wants me to go away.
No. he doesn't.
But he doesn't know...
He doesn't know what?
Samara?
She's never gonna whisper
in my fucking ear ever again!
What did you do to her?
She was your daughter!
You killed Samara.
didn't you?
You killed her.
and when your wife--
My wife was not supposed
to have a child!
Mr. Morgan...
What are you doing?
The whispers... you could
hear them all the time.
At night. In your sleep.
Even the damn horses.
Mr. Morgan. come out of there.
And those pictures.
Oh. Good Christ.
The things she'd show you.
She's still showing them.
And she'll never stop.
You coming here proves that.
Where is she? Please.
I have to stop her.
If I don't. my son will die!
Oh. yes.
He will.
She never sleeps.
Wait. No...
No!
Rachel! Shh! Shh!
It's all right!
Shh. shh. shh. shh. shh.
It's okay. It's okay.
You're okay.
Shh. shh. shh!
You okay?
Oh. Jesus.
She doesn't like the barn.
The horses keep her up
at night.
She doesn't like the barn.
What?
The horses keep her awake.
Samara...
He kept her here.
Her mother was going crazy.
Morgan blamed the child.
So he kept her here.
Alone.
Not alone.
Rachel...
There's something under here.
It looks like
it's etched into the wood.
Or burned.
I've seen this tree before.
Yeah. it was on the tape.
No.
I've been there.
Shelter Mountain.
The sun came through the leaves.
lit them up like it was on fire.
Right at sunset.
Right when I watched the tape.
That was a week ago.
We're back to where
we started from.
Something led us here.
The tree.
the drawing on the wall--
It doesn't matter.
We're too late.
You have to help him.
What are you talking about?
Aidan.
It's up to you now.
Just use the time you have
and figure something out.
We'll figure this out
together. right now!
It's too late. Noah!
Stop it. okay? There's a reason
that we're here!
-What?!
-I don't know. okay?
There's something in this room!
I mean. it's in this phone!
It's in this television!
Come on!
Tell us now. why don't you?!
Noah...
look.
Aw. Jesus.
How far down
do you think it goes?
I can't see anything.
We should drop something.
Do you think
she's down there?
Shh...
Rachel!
I'm here!
I'm all right!
I think.
I'll go find something
to get you out!
Hurry!
Noah?
Noah!
Oh!
Here we go
The world is spinning
When it stops.
it's just beginning.
Isn't it beautiful here. Samara?
So peaceful.
I know things will get better.
All I ever wanted was you.
She was still alive.
Where did you go?
It's okay now.
It's okay.
Rachel!
Rachel. the sun's set!
The sun has set!
It's past sunset.
Do you hear me?
It's past sunset!
Rachel?
Rachel. are you there?
I'm here.
They're going to bury her
next week.
It's over.
You okay?
She wanted that child
more than anything in the world.
How could she have done that?
She just wanted to be heard.
Sometimes children...
yell or cry or draw pictures.
I want to go home.
I can't imagine being stuck
down a well all alone like that.
How long could you survive?
Seven days.
You could survive
for seven days.
Come on.
Hey.
Why don't you just
call me sometime?
Unless you're renting a movie.
Call me tomorrow...
...and the day after that.
Rachel?
Hmm?
What time is it?
It's either really late
or really early...
depending on how you look at it.
Don't you have to be at work?
Not today.
What happened to the girl?
Samara?
Is that her name?
Mm-hmm.
Is she still in the dark place?
No.
We set her free.
You helped her?
Yeah.
Why did you do that?
What's wrong. honey?
You weren't supposed
to help her.
It's okay now.
She's not going to hurt you.
She...
Don't you understand. Rachel?
She never sleeps.
Pick up the phone. Noah.
Come on. pick up.
Come on. Noah!
Pick up the goddamn phone!
Come on!
Go to your room!
Now!
What do you want?
What do you want?!
What do you want from me?
Why not me?
What did I do that he didn't?
She just wanted to be heard.
He wants me to go away.
My wife was not supposed
to have a child!
All I ever wanted was you.
Don't you understand. Rachel?
But he doesn't know.
She never sleeps.
You take one person's tragedy
and force the world
to experience it.
You spread it like sickness.
You don't want to hurt anyone.
But I do.
And I'm sorry.
It won't stop.
I made a copy.
Push it in.
''Play.''
Push.
It's going to keep killing.
isn't it?
She'll never stop.
Don't worry. sweetie.
You're going to be okay.
What about the person
we show it to?
What happens to them?